# SANTHOSH R.

9442357408 \$\prim \text{Nilgiris, TamilNadu, IN}

rsanthosh411998@gmail.com ♦ linkedin.com/santhoshr ♦ www.santhoshravi.com

Software Engineer with 2+ years of Professional Work experience in Software Industry. Always willing to work in a challenging environment that provides opportunities for learning, creative thinking and innovation

## **EDUCATION**

XII - Higher Sec. Education, Stanes Anglo Indian Higher Sec School, Coonoor - 94.5 percent 2013 - 2015 B.E Computer Science Engineering, College of Engineering Guindy(CEG), Chennai - 85.1 percent 2015 - 2019

## **SKILLS**

Technical Skills C++, JavaScript, SQL, C#, Python, JAVA, React, Redux, ASP.Net, HandleBars, Jquery, Elastic

Tools Git, Azure Devops, Jenkins, Octopus, Google Tag Manager, Google Analytics

Interests Data Structures and Algorithms, Web Development, Analytics

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer Intern - Xome, Chennai

Jan 2019 - July 2019

- Implemented Monitoring Metrics for Xome Auctions Product with the help of Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics improving Site Metrics using JavaScript.
- Developed Portal for BSA and Admin Users to update Auctions Listing Banners and Listing Images to avoid deployment for each and every content change using C# Javascript and Jquery.

## Software Engineer - Xome , Chennai

July 2019 - Oct 2021

- Developed features for Auctions Platform including Real time Bid ability for Users, Event Registration for properties with a Credit Card Hold, Preventing Fake Users from doing Auctions transactions by implementing Account Verification Mechanisms like S.M.S, Email token Verification using C#, JavaScript, HandleBars JS, SQL and Elastic Search. (https://www.xome.com/auctions)
- Designed and Implemented Help Center Section in Auctions based a Dynamic Data Driven JSON Model with the help of Caching Mechanism and Cache Eviction done with FIFO using Memcache and Custom built JSON Parser. (https://www.xome.com/auctions/help-center)
- Built Dynamic City level and State Level footer enabling users for easy Navigation and to improve the Search Engine Optimization Crawling for the Auctions Application using C#, SQL Jobs and Handlebars JS.
- Revamped Legacy Login by developing a Common SignIn/SignUp Modal based on Forms Based Authentication and brought up Low Login Latency using Javascript and Jquery.

## Software Engineer - BungeeTech, Chennai

PRESENT

## **PROJECTS**

Serverless Whatsapp Chatbot. Built a Serverless Weather Chatbot in AWS Lex with the help of Custom Intents and Utterances integrated with external Third Party Service Twilio for Programmable Whatsapp Messaging consuming weather data API's from WeatherStack using Python. (ChatBot)

Cognitive Based Personality Trait Identification (PTI) using Emotion Recognition from EEG Signals Built a Peronality Trait Identification System from EEG Signals using SVM Classifier for Emotion Recognition and Cognitive Mapping using Hebbian Algorithm with the help of Python.

Single Sign-on (SSO) Authentication. Implemented SSO login for Personal Portfolio Application with the help of Azure Active Directory consuming Azure Directory Federation Service (ADFS) and handled Auth token plus refresh token in Windows Credentials Manager

## ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Star Award for Best Performance in Xome Q4 2020.
  IT 3C's 2nd Qtr 2021 Cheerleader in Xome.
- Student Director at Computer Science Society of Anna University.